# Zhitong Gao

 ♦ Homepage | 
 Google Scholar | 
 Of GitHub | 
 OpenReview | 
 Email

## Summary

I am a final-year master's student in Computer Science at ShanghaiTech University, supervised by Prof. Xuming He. My research focuses primarily on Computer Vision and Deep Learning, where I concentrate on developing robust and safe dense prediction models under uncertainty, specializing in areas like learning with noisy labels, uncertainty estimation, out-of-distribution detection, domain generalization and test-time adaptation.

#### EDUCATION

## ShanghaiTech University

M.S. in Computer Science, supervised by Xuming He;

Cumulative GPA: 3.87/4.00; Major GPA: 3.94/4.00;

École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne (EPFL)

Visiting Scholar at CV Lab, supervised by Mathieu Salzmann;

ShanghaiTech University

B.E. in Computer Science; GPA: 3.62/4.00;

University of California, Berkeley

Participant in Summer School Session E;

Shanghai, China

Sep. 2021 - Jun. 2024 (Expected)

Lausanne, Switzerland

Sep. 2023 - Apr. 2024 (Expected)

Shanghai, China

Sep. 2017 - Jun. 2021

Berkeley, USA Summer 2019

# PUBLICATIONS

- Zhitong Gao, Shipeng Yan, Xuming He. "ATTA: Anomaly-aware Test-Time Adaptation for Out-of-Distribution Detection in Segmentation." Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2023. [Paper] [Code]
- Bingnan Li, **Zhitong Gao**, Xuming He. "Gradient-Map-Guided Adaptive Domain Generalization for Cross Modality MRI Segmentation" Proceedings of Machine Learning for Health (ML4H), 2023. [Paper] [Code]
- Zhitong Gao, Yucong Chen, Chuyu Zhang, Xuming He. "Modeling Multimodal Aleatoric Uncertainty in Segmentation with Mixture of Stochastic Experts." International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2023. [Paper] [Code]
- Chuanyang Hu, Shipeng Yan, **Zhitong Gao**, Xuming He. "MILD: Modeling the Instance Learning Dynamics for Learning with Noisy Labels." International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2023. [Paper] [Code]
- Shuailin Li\*, **Zhitong Gao**\*, Xuming He. "Superpixel-guided Iterative Learning from Noisy Labels for Medical Image Segmentation." International Conference on Medical Image Computing and Computer Assisted Intervention (MICCAI), 2021. (\* indicates equal contribution.) [Paper] [Code]

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

# Dense Out-of-Distribution Detection with Domain Shift.

Advisor: Mathieu Salzmann, Xuming He

2023 - Present

- Distinguish domain-level and semantic-level distribution shifts.
- Jointly study out-of-distribution detection and domain generalization.

#### Test-Time Adaptation for Dense Out-of-Distribution Detection.

Advisor: Xuming He

2022 - 2023

- Propose a dual-level OOD detection framework that addresses both domain shift and semantic shift in real-world cenarios, improving the accuracy of existing OOD detection models.
- Validate the effectiveness of the proposed method on multiple OOD segmentation benchmarks, including those with significant domain shifts and those without, demonstrating consistent performance gains.
- The relevant paper has been accepted in NeurIPS 2023.

#### Aleatoric Uncertainty in Segmentation

Advisor: Xuming He 2021-2022

- Explicitly model the multimodal characteristic of aleatoric uncertainty in segmentation in a form of mixture of stochastic experts. Each expert encodes a distinct mode and its weight represents the mode probability.
- Formulate the model learning as an Optimal-Transport problem and design a Wasserstein-like loss that directly minimizes the distribution distance between the model and ground truth annotations.
- The relevant paper has been accepted in ICLR 2023.

## Segmentation of Myocardial Infarction Area from a single T2-STIR MRI image.

Advisor: Xuming He, Lianming Wu

2021 - 2022

- Design an automatic cross-modal segmentation system capable of predicting chronic myocardial infarction (MI) regions marked in LGE images based on the corresponding non-enhanced cardiac MRI images. This system needs to cope with the misalignment between the two modalities.
- The proposed model shows satisfactory performance in MI area prediction and provides a calibrated uncertainty score map that facilitates interpreting the reliability of predictions in practice.
- In submission to European Heart Journal.

## Learning Dynamics for noisy labels

Advisor: Xuming He

2021 - 2022

- Propose a novel selection metric based on the learning dynamics of each data instance. This metric provides a more robust reference for label uncertainty than small-loss trick, as it collects information across various training stages.
- Achieve the state of the art on five popular noisy image classification benchmarks including synthetic noisy datasets and real-world web data.
- The relevant paper has been accepted in IJCAI 2023.

#### Learning with noisy labels in Segmentation

Advisor: Xuming He

2020 - 2021

- Adopt a superpixel representation and develop a robust iterative learning strategy that combines noise-aware training of segmentation network and noisy label refinement, both guided by the superpixels.
- This design enables us to exploit the structural constraints in segmentation labels and effectively mitigate the impact of label noise in learning.
- The relevant paper has been accepted in MICCAI 2021.

#### Challenges and Selected Course Projects

### Robust Energy Score for MUAD Challenge | Paper

- MUAD Uncertainty Estimation for Semantic Segmentation Challenge, ICCV Workshop, 2023.
- Adaptively adjust Batch Normalization layers to enable robust OOD detection with various weather conditions.

## Bilayer Ensemble Semantic Segmentation for QUBIQ Challenge | Poster

- Quantification of Uncertainties in Biomedical Image Quantification (QUBIQ) Challenge 2021.
- We propose an ensemble of raters, each of whom is trained individually with corresponding experts, thereby enabling them to learn specific characteristics.

#### Generalized DUQ: Generalized Deterministic Uncertainty Quantification | Report

- Final Project of CS282 Machine Learning, ShanghaiTech University
- We proposed an extension to DUQ, called Generalized DUQ, that expands the original uncertainty estimation from using only its nearest centroid, to using the nearest 'k' centroids.

#### Seek Common while Shelving Differences: A New Way for dealing with Noisy Labels | Report

- Final Project of CS280 Deep Learning, Shanghai Tech University
- We proposed SCSD, a tri-net framework that combines the benefits of 'cross training' and 'agreement', offering a novel approach to handling noisy labels.

#### AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

National Scholarship for Graduate Excellence (2023), ShanghaiTech University Outstanding Student (2020), ShanghaiTech University Merit Student (2019).

#### Relevant Coursework

Deep Learning A+, Computer Vision II A+, Optimization and Machine Learning A+, Online learning and Optimization A+, Natual Language Processing A, Digital Image Analysis A, Probability and Statistics A.

### PROFESSIONAL SERVICE

Peer Reviewer for CVPR 2023, NeurIPS 2023, CVPR 2024; Teaching Assistant for CS280 Deep Learning, 2022 Fall.